MARKO HENRIK HAUTALA

Full stack Software Developer

github.com/markohautala / linkedin.com/in/markohautala Stockholm, Sweden / markohautala@live.se / 072-291-07-50



Executive Summary

My name is Marko, and I am a passionate and enthusiastic Full Stack Developer with a love for frontend development. I code everyday and I have experience and strong knowledge in JavaScript, Python, React, Nextjs, Django, Bootstrap, databases, HTML/CSS, and working with APIs. I also have skills in AI/ML, NodeJS, SQL, Flask and with AWS. I strive to create smooth UX/user-friendly interfaces with modern principles and robust, clean backends. My attention to detail, strong analytical abilities, and quick problem-solving skills are among my strengths.

I am looking for chances to use my skills in a collaborative team. I am always eager to upskill and get better. With over 9 years of overall experience working well with teams as well as independently, communicating effectively and for the last three years, being a team leader, I have outstanding references that show my excellent service, strong results, and positive impact on my colleagues.

Education

Jun 2023 - Aug 2024	Code Institute	Dublin, Ireland (Remote Based Learning)
	Diploma in Full Stack Software Development -	
	Advanced front-end specialization. 30 ECTS. (Accredited by the University West of Scotland). Done in august.	
Sept 2018 - Jun 2021	Stockholm University &	Stockholm, Sweden
	The Swedish School of Sport and Health Sciences Physical education (PE) teacher. 180 ECTS.	

Technical Skill Set

Client-side	Server-side	Development & operations
HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Bootstrap, jQuery, Tailwind, NextJS, ThreeJS	Python, SQL/NoSQL-databases, Django/DjangoREST, Flask, Jinja, MongoDB, JSON, TypeScript	Agile, Jest-testing, CI/CD, Git, GitHub, Heroku, API:s, DevTools, Figma, VSCode, GitHub Copilot, Vercel, OpenAI, Azure

Portfolio Projects

- 1. **Nextjs OpenAI API Chat-app** AI/Chat-GPT like app for coders that also can take regular non-code user prompts can display code using React syntax-highlighter. **Tech used:** Nextjs, AI, TypeScript, Tailwind, JavaScript, Vercel, API:s, OpenAI. Link:
 - https://github.com/markohautala/nextjs-tailwind-ai-chat/tree/master
- 2. **Django Auth and CRUD app** Application with full CRUD-functionality and user Authentication. **Tech used:** Python / Django framework, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL-database, Heroku. Link: https://github.com/markohautala/django-auth-crud-app

- 3. **React to-do app with background animation** To-do application built and based on React. **Tech used:** React, JavaScript, Vite, Three.js, Heroku, HTML, CSS. Link: https://github.com/markohautala/react-app
- 4. **Flask Project** Website developed using the Flask framework. **Tech used:** Flask, Python, Jinja, HTML, jQuery, CSS, JSON. Link: https://github.com/markohautala/Flask-project
- 5. **Bootstrap Online Resume** Online resume built with Bootstrap. **Tech Used:** HTML, CSS, API:s, Bootstrap, emailJS, JavaScript. Link: https://markohautala.github.io/bootstrap-online-resume/

Work Experience

Fornuddens school - Tyresö, Stockholm

Physical Education (PE) teacher

Aug. 2021 - Present

- **Active Listening and Communication:** I engage in daily communication and collaboration with various school stakeholders, enhancing effective teamwork and understanding of different needs.
- Stress Management and Time Management: I handle teaching responsibilities, administrative tasks, and documentation under tight deadlines, demonstrating excellent stress management and time management skills.
- **Decision Making and Problem Solving:** Teamleader over six colleagues, making quick decisions and solving unexpected issues efficiently, showing strong leadership and critical thinking abilities.
- **Organization and Adaptability:** I initiate and manage projects to improve work routines, displaying organizational skills, multitasking ability, and adaptability to new challenges.

Kaffeknappen AB - Stockholm, Sweden

Service & Customer Relations Manager

June 2016 - June 2018

- **High responsibility:** Managed and had full responsibility over exclusive coffee machines for 100 large companies in Södermalm, maintaining high service standards. All customers were very satisfied.
- **Problem-solving and adaptability:** I retained Kaffeknappen's largest corporate client by resolving previous dissatisfaction, earning positive feedback (see reference).
- **Time management and self-motivation:** I showed strong independence, responsibility, and efficiency in meeting deadlines.

Certificates/Collaborative Projects

- **AI foundations** Machine Learning
- Hackathon (agile collaboration with six team members) built a website to calculate investment profitability using NPV.

 https://ou.badgr.com/public/assertions/7PUiJUAO2RE2mJiw8ShOEw2identity_omail=markshout.

 $\underline{https://eu.badgr.com/public/assertions/ZRUiU4Q2R52vnIjw8SbO5w?identity \ email=markohautala@live.se}$

Additional Information/Interests

- Listening continuously to tech podcasts like "Developers!" and "HTML All the things" to stay updated with the software/IT-industry. I also regularly engage in coding communities like the Slack tech forum.
- Strong interest in different Al-technologies.
- Coding on personal portfolio projects every day.
- High interests in self-improvement, fitness, food and nutrition.
- I both speak, read and write fluently in Swedish, English and Finnish.

Kaffeknappen AB

"Regarding Marko, I cannot praise him enough. He provides fantastic service and maintains a very professional attitude with customers. He is an incredibly important ambassador for the company Kaffeknappen. It is rare to see such a young man take on such comprehensive responsibility towards customers.

Best regards,

A very satisfied customer (DN - Dagens Nyheter)."

More references available on request.